地震过后 我希望最糟糕的时期已经过去了
After the tremors | hoped the worst was Over.
我希望周围的世界能恢复正音
| wished the world around me would return to _ normal，
可是 当我穿过路障重重的街道时
instead, as 1 | barricaded streets
我感觉到关于地震的记忆依然存在
1felt the memory of the earthquake had endured，
成了那不勒斯的一部分
Naples contained it.
我写不出来东西 做不了任何决定
| couldnt write anymore, make any decisions,
我假妆与尼话一切都好
| pretended everything was fine with Nino.
我不停地被路边的俯石绊倒
| kept tripping over the rubble
我的内心也是一片废坊
that was now deep inside me, too.
莱农 你看起来很惟迟 你要多吃肉
Lenuw, you look run down. You need to eat more meat my |ove.
我不喜欢吃肉
| dont like meat
那融学着喜欢
Learn to like 放.
我怀你的时候 胖了快四十斤
When 1was pregnant with you, | put on 44 pounds.
更别襄怀佩佩的时候了
Not to mention with Peppe.
你坐着吧 我来铺
Sit down, 川| do 并
你最近见莉娜了吗
Have you seen Lila?
没有 我和她打过电话
No, | spoke to her on the phone.
她皇么样 挺好的
你和她襄了佩修和入尼工作的事吗
Did you ask her about Peppe and Gianni?
没有 那你什么时候说
No. When are you gonna do it?
我不想他们在索拉拉那里工作
| dont like them working under the Solarasl
我不喜欢 妈妈 莉娜没法给他们安排工作
| dont like it. But Lila can't give them jobs.
她一边要应付里诺 他已经吸毒成交了
She has to deal with Rino messed up on drugs.
一边还要操心久纳罗 她根本顾不上其他
And she's worried about Gennaro .Its too much to ask of herl
你别担心
Dont worry，
总能想到办法解决的
welfigure something out.
我回你保证
| promise.
最初 我部种给索拉拉干活 她是接受的
She used to be fine with my brothers under Marcello.
但她现在害怕了
But now She was scared .
她认为责任在我 因为我没有帮助他们学习
She said | was responsible as | hadn't helped them to study.
她确实让我感到很内多
Sometimes she actually made me feel guilty.
佩佩
好了 去吧
Now beat it
二么了
Whaddaya want?
你喜欢利用人们的痛天赚钱 是吗
You like earning from people's misery?
你什么意思 什么意思
What do you mean? What?
你看到那两个人的状态了吗
Did you see the state those two were in?
你大老远跑来融是为了说这些
You came all the way here to Say this?
去做其他任何工作 除了这个 它会贤了你的
Do any other job, but not this, 风l ruin you.
莱农 没有其他工作
Thet are no jobs, Lenu.
你难道没意识到
You don't realize 放
你和和詹尼这样 会让妈妈担心死的
but you and Gianni 人 kill Mamma with worry.
舌 好笑吗
Yeah, laugh.…
没有我的钱 妈妈早融死了
Without my money Mamma'd be dead already.
别担心 再见
Don't worry. Goodbye.
拜拜 祝好哦
Goodbye', take care.
屁股好痛啊
What a pain in the ass.
莱农 来让我亲亲
Lenw, let me give you a kiss.
还有多久生啊 不久 最后一个月了
How long? Not long, the end of the month.
和玛丽亚一样
Like Maria
她惑是1月27 28号生的 好像是在半夜
She was born between the 27th and 28th of January at 11:30pm.
者娜和客户在一起 恩佐很快残回来
Lila's with a client_ Enzo will be back Soon
你要等等吗 好
Will you wait? Yes.
我接个电话残过来陪你 不用了 艾达 没事的
川 call someone to keep you company. There's no need.
阿方索 过来
Alfonso, come.
茉农来了
Lenuccia's here.
Lennw.
见到你好开心啊
What a surprise.
米绩茉也在
Michele's here too
隆 米纪茉
Hi Michele.
你什么时候变得这么正式了
Since when did you become so formal?
你现在出名了 会给人一点压力
Youre famous now, its intimidating.
我们还没适应呢
We're not used to 放.
得了吧
Knock it offl
真厉害
Good.
你很厉害 很勇敢 为什么
You're good and brave. Why?
你已经有两个孩子了
You already had two kids.
言耀拉跟我说 你们分开了
Gigliola told me you're separated.
我也离婚了
|m separated too.
我知道
| know.
我还知道你跟谁在一起呢
And | know who you're with too.
人融得做目己想做的事 否则融会生病
People have to do what they feel like, or Fe get Sick.
我也快离婚了
lm getting separated too.
玛丽水 你的尼诺他妹妹 心里只有钱
Marisa, your Nino's little sister thinks only about money.
我把全部的钱都给她了 但永远不够
| gave her everything | had but its never enough.
她不知道卡拉奇家没钱了 我哥也是
The Carraccis' money is gone, So is my brother S.
忠之 无可款何
No two ways about 比
女人会量无顾忌地把男人 从其他女人身边抢走
women men away from other women, without any scruples.
但其实 我还挺高兴航
Actually with great satisfaction.
跟跳华尔妇似的
What a waltz:
艾达从者娜身边抢走斯特凡诺 现在玛丽沙又抢了艾达的
Ada took stefano from Lila and now Marisa's taking.…
阿方索 我能和茉农聊会吗
Alfonso, can |talk to Lenuccia?
你母亲怎么样
How's your mother?
不是很好
Not good.
他们在兰试一些新的治疗方法 但她已经筋疲力尽了
They're trying some new treatments, but she's exhausted.
我弟弟们给你哥哥干活 她很不开心
9he's not happy that my brothers work for your brother.
马尔切洛有什么地万做得不对的吗
Whats wrong with Marcello?
你来告诉我
You tel| me.
我知道你们相处得不好
| know you don't get along.
那你融钞了
You got wrong 语J
如果你母杀不喜欢马尔切洛的钱
fyour mother doesn't like Marcello's money,
她可以让两个儿子去别人的手下干啊
she can Send them to work elsewhere.
虽 今天人真多啊
What a crowd
你有话和我说吗
You need to talk to me?
需要很长时间吗
Will ittake long?
那么 我先和莱农聊吧
Then, 川talk to Lenuccia first.
他不是为了工作来的
He's not here for work
他在找俐口
He makes up exCcuses.
但你别插手
But you stay out of it.
我只说一遍
| wont Say it again
我没法不插手
1 cant stay out of it
马尔切洛会贤了佩侦和和詹尼
Marcello's ruining Peppe and Gianni.
我必须做点什么 必须面对他
| have to confront him .
这也不是你可以插手的事 还是在航特拉克街上待着吧
This too, you cant interfere then go back up to Via Petrarcal.
我不希望我母亲 因为担心两个儿子和死不肯目
1cant let my mom take her last breath worried about her sons.
你要让她放心 霸么放心
Comfort her How?
详言比镇静剂还管用
Lies are better than tranquilizers.
那你会对我说诉吗
Do you lie to me?
我什么都不会襄
Im not saying anything.
不听劝的人才是真正的碍束
None are deafer than those who will not hear.
参赛者的分数从30000下降到20000
..the contestant's score has gone downm, ffrom 30,000 to 20,000.
所以一等奖从300万降到了200万
The jackpots gone from 3 million to 2 million.
5只是想和大家这清楚这一操
|just wanted to make this clear.
好了 在你看来 1980年意大利的关键问题是什么
In your opinion, what are, for better or for worse，
无论好坏 在未来几年都会被人们铭记的那种
the key issues in ltaly in 1980 thatll be remembered in years to come?
物价上涨
Price increaSseS
几乎像是在遵守一个诺言 柯希莫再也没有从树上下来
"...Cosimo will never come down from the trees again."
焉为了一盘蜗牛吗
For a plate of snails?
换做你 你会吃吗 我才不吃呢 多恶心啊
Would you have eaten them? Not me, yuckl
好搞笑的名字啊 柯希莫:迪`隆多
What a funny name, Cosimo di Rondo.
他是个贵族 贵族的名字都很摘关
He was a noble and nobles have funny names.
他后来还见过维奥拉吗
Does he see Viola again?
他们结婚了吗
Do they get married?
下次再给你们讲 现在大晚了
川tell you next time, its gotten late.
我们睡觉吧 不要嘛
Let's go to bed. No.…
来吧 真棒
Yes. Good girl.
来 杀一下
Let's do this
现在 你们好好睡觉吧
You go to sleep now.…
我明天讲后面的故事
and tomorrow Itell you how it ends.
要是明天你不来呢
What fyou don't come?
我会来的
|上川come.
这是震后
Its the first step of an important initiative
重要举措的第一步
of the post-earthquake efforts.
经过漫长的辩论之后 市政厅批准了一项倡议
An initiative approved by City Hall after a long debate.…
由于一些紧急情况
你对你儿子了解多少
What do you know about your Son?
什和 么意  三思
What do you mean?
西尔维亚的儿子 米尔科
Silvia's son Mirko.
我在马丽妍罗沙家里见过他
| saw him when | was at Mariarosa'S.
你认他了吗
Did you acknowledge him?
你照顾过他吗
Have you ever dt anything for him?
你不想见他吗 他和你长得一模一样
Arent you curious to see him? He's identical to you.
有时候我真不台道拿你怎么办 帮有帮忙 好吗
Sometimes | dont know what to do with you help me out.
Do what? Explain.
我不知道
| dont know.
你是个很取明的女人 但有时候吧
Youre an intelligent woman, but sometimes.…
你融像另一个人一样
it's like you're Someone else.
也融是况 无理取疝 很电酸吗
Meaning? Unreasonable, stupid?
你六听者娜的话了
You listen to Lila too much .
你听她话的时候融会变得电台
When you listen to her you LS 全
今 今晚   我想一个人 睡
人  | want to sleep alone.
好吧
All right.
喂 役得罗 抱歉 这么晚打扰你
Helloy Pietro, Sorry, it's So late.
生么了 我觉得我要生了
Whats up? 1think the time's come.
你现在难受吗 明天你来接女儿们吧
Come and get the girls tomorrow. Are you in pain?
好 但你现在皇么样了 很难受吗 不 我还好
No, lm fine.
你怎么去医院 我会请邻居帮忙
How will you get there? 川 ask my neighbor.
随时跟我联系
Please keep me posted.
当然 我晚点会打给你 拜
Yes, 川 call you later. Bye.
我快生了 我得去医院
Its time, | have to get to the hospital.
你能帮有我照看一下女儿吗
Wilyou look after the girls?
等等 页科莫可以开车送你去
Wait Giacomo can drive you.
不用了 我目己去 您么去
No, 川 go alone. How will you go?
川| drive.
快点去照看我女儿啊 拜托了 好的
Please go straightaway. Yes.
谢谢 别客气
Thank you. Not at all.
早上好
Good morning.
谁告诉你的
Who told you?
今天早上我回家找你
This morning | came home to spend some time with you.
Te Was no on人 订  | ,了 and rushed over here.
这是谁呀
Who's this?
是谁啊
你怎么样
How are you?
她在睡觉吗
ls she sleeping?
现在我们是四个广的 假如你离开我的话 我也可以理解
Now we're four females, | understand ifyou leave me.
我的生活不能没有你
| cant live without you.
也不能没有她
And without her.
她很乖
She's good.
我市了个小东西
1 got a little something.
太漂吉了 你喜欢吗
Its beautiful. Do you like it?
喜欢 谢谢
Yes, thank you.
你能帮我戴上吗
Wilyou put it on?
把头皮报起来 咽
Lift your hair.
好看吗
Look okay?
这条项链真的很适合你
It really suits you.
Hello?
埃莱娜 役得罗 了
Elena. Pietro, hi.
你还好吗 是的 一切顺利
Are you all right? Yes, everything's fine.
孩子皇么样 她7磅重
How's the baby? She weighs seven pounds.
有点秃现的 但很可爱
She's a little bald, but she's cute.
可能她长得有点像和信介
Maybe she looks a bit like Dede.
我等不及要看看她了 好啊
| cant wait to meet her. Right.
越早越好 我等不及让你们看看她了
As soon as possible. | want you all to see her.
尼诺跟你在一起吗 对
ls Nino with you? Yes.
孩子们交给我了 你好好休息吧
Ilook after the girls, you rest.
我爱你 我也是
| love you. Me too.
一会儿见 好的 拜拜
1 see you soon. All right. Bye.
我想给堂.克劳迪奥打个电话
on Claudio.
他是我的一个老朋友
old friend of min
你真的想给她洗礼吗 孩子都是要洗礼的
Do you really want to baptize her? Children get baptized.
阿尔伯特和者迪亚都受洗了吗 当然
Are Albertino and Lidia baptized? Of course.
你是个信徒吗 不是
But are you a believer? No.
我以为你是
|thought you were. Me?
你为什么这么想
Why would you think that?
你高中时和宗教老师争论
You used to argue with the religion teacher in high school.
你否定了他 但你当时很投入
You contested him, but you were very into it.
无论如何 不管我们是不是信徒 孩子都要进行洗礼
Anyway, believers or not children get baptized.
这是什么逻辑 不是远辑
What sort of reasoning is that? Its not reasoning.
是情感 /5
证 Ss a feeling.
你不要让我前后矛盾 我没给售复和艾尔沙洗礼
1 want to be consistent 1 didn't baptize Dede and Elsa
我也不会给她洗礼
and 1dont want to baptize her either.
她们长大了 可以自己决定
They can decide when they grow up.
谁在乎呢 洗礼也只是为了庆祝一下
Who cares, its an occasion to throw a party.
我们会庆祝的 是吗
Let's throw one anyway. YeS?
好了 现在弄好了
All done.
抱菊 我还是不知道怎么使用复印机
Im sorry 1still dont know how to use the photocopier.
格雷科女十 您和这位乔瓦尼`萨拉托雷先生是夫妻吗
9Signora Greco, youre married to the here present Giovanni Sarratore?
是的
YeS.
不 抱歉
No, |m Sorry.
我和彼得罗-艾罗塔离婚了
lm separated from Pietro Airota.
然后呢 现在的叉夫是
And so, married to?
没有 没有藉夫
No._ To no one .
你的单住地是 役特拉克路127号
Your residential address? 127 Via Petrarca
不 我只是暂时住在那里 对
No, Im only domiciled there. Right.
我是佛罗伦萨的居民
Il'Im a resident of Florence.
圣母领报广场24号
24 Piazza Santissima Annunziata .
你们至少知道给孩子起什么名字吧
Do you at least have a name forthe baby?
我们之前定的什么
What did we decide on?
伊马可拉塔
Immacolata.
伊马可拉才
Immacolata?
伊马可拉塔萨拉托雷
Immacolata Sarratore.
是的 伊马可拉塔院拉托雷 是的
Yes, Immacolata Sarratore. That's right.
我的天哪
Goodness me.
兴 但同时色有举迷王
d disoriented at the same time.
这是我一直深爱着的那个男人吗
Was he the man | had always loved，
还是一个卫生人
orastranger1was forcing
航我强迫着承认 目己是我们女儿的父杀
to take on a definitive status as the father of our daughter?
我刚生产完的那几天 尼庄放下了所有事儿
In those early days, Nino neglected his countless commitments.
向我展示我对他有多么重要
He was demonstrating how much | meant to him.
我把包放下
川 put the bags down.
我的任何一个杀威
None of my relatives came to the clinic.
还有城区的任何一个朋友 都没来诊所看我
None of my friends from the neighborhood.
我把我的出身和我的生活彻撒分开了
1 distanced myself from my past
我感竞那种彻底的决肥
So that | could feel a clear-cut separation
那是我生命中最脆弱阶段的残余
from the fragile periods of my life.
几乎是一种不成熟的象征
Htwas a sign of immaturity.
Hello?
莱农 我在你妈妈家 她想来看你 我寓她过去
Lenu, your mom wants to come see you. 川 bring her over.
二|
人E
天和气这么冷 让她出来不太好吧
In this cold its bad for her to go oult.
我已经跟她说了 但她不听
| told herthat but she won't listen.
这几天我会办一场聚会 邀请你们所有人来
In a few days, 川 have a party and invite you al.
到时候她融能看到孩子了
She'l see her Soon.
现在尼庄在这里
Nino's here.
我把电话给她 你跟她说吧
川 put her on, you can tell her.
不算了
No, dont.
那我等着你们
川 expect you, then.
是者娜
上waSs Lila.
我母亲想过来
My mother wants to come over.
那很好啊
That's good.
现在 她们现在残在来的路上
Now, they're coming now.
我们收拾一下 有什么问题吗
Welltidqy up a bit what's the big deal?
你去药店吧 我和她们喝杯咖啡
You go to the drugstore while 1 have coffee with them.
不 我在这里等着她们
No, 川lwait for them.
想回你母杀问好
1d like to say hello to your mother.
没事的
Right little one?
你来照看她吗 看看 她多漂亮
Wil you take care of her? Look how beautiful.
你能照看好她吗 当然
Wil you take care of her? Yes.
我觉得这场拜访 融像一场强行闻入
| took that visit as an intrusion.
我现在还很疲伯
| still felt tired
而且最重要的是 尼诺在家
and above all Nino was in the house.
我不希惧我母亲看到他生气
1didnt want to upset my mom.…
而且 在我身体没有恢复的情况下 看到尼诺和者娜再次站在一块
but it also made me uneasy that Nino and Lila would be side by side again,
会让我很不目在
at atime when | wasnt in shape yet.
进来吧
Come in.
关上门 很冷
Close it it's cold.
妈妈 尼诡也在这儿
Mamma, Nino's here too.
早上好 伊马可拉塔女士
Good morning, Signora Immacolata.
坐这里吧 这边景色很好
Sit here, there's a nice view.
海湾真美啊
How beautiful the bay is.
坐吧
Sit down .
你们喝点什么吗
Can loffer you Something?
来杯水吧
Aglass of water?
我们去把孩子抱过来
Let's go get the baby.
这从哪来的
And that?
尼话送给我的
Nino gave it to me.
尔喜欢她吗
Do you like her?
降
YeS.
谁知道我的会是什么样
Who knows what mine's |ike.
他会很乖 很漂之
He'l be beautiful and good.
要是我生了儿子 咱们换一下
f not we can do a swap.
下雪了 今年的维苏威火山一定美极了
With this sprinkling of snow Vesuvius is beautiful this year.
更小的房子 那边是索伦托
Where the |ower houses are js Sorrento
那是卡普里岛
Capris over there.
您看不到伊斯基亚马 因为在后面挡住了
You can't see |Sschia because it's behind there.
喝点水吗
Some Water?
看看谁来啦
Look who's here.
这是伊马可拉塔
This is Immacolata.
这名字真好听 文士
Its a beautiful name, signora.
不 不好听
No, its not.
但你们可以叫她伊玛 更时尚一操
But you can call her Imma, its more modern.
要喝咖啡吗 噢 我筷记了
The coffee? | forgot.
让我抱抱她 给
Let me hold her for aa moment
你抱得动吗 当然了
Can you manage?
怀子在这儿
The cups are here.
SEE区                 SEE雪
漂腕啊   太漂亮
Beautiful, beautifu|.
她和你长得真像
She looks like you.
你给了我这样大的司喜
You gave me this surprise.
咖啡来了
Here's the coffee
大哪
Oh Godl
妈妈
Mammal
伍么了
Whats wrong?
让她坐下
Let's Sit her down .
YA人二
/一日
Calm down.
没事的
Its nothing.
慢慢来
Slowly does it.
市她去医院吧 不 我不去医院
Let's take her to the hospital. No, 1m not going to the hospital.
我去叫救护车 好
川| call an ambulan
莱农 等救护车要很久
An ambulance will take forever.
我开车市她过去 好 把她抱起来
让 take her in the car. Yes. Hang up.
我妈妈的主治医师认识艾罗塔家族
The doctor treating my mom knows Eleonora's family.
尼庄市她过去是最好的办法
It's best 计 Nino takes her.
茉农   我不想死在 医 院
1dont wanna die in the hospitall
我想看看孩子
1 want to see the baby.…
我不想走
1dont wanna gol
只是去做个检查而已
Its just for a checkup.
者娜 我们走吧
Lila, let's go.
您到我身上来吧
Hold onto me.
来 把孩子给我吧 你跟着过去
Leave the baby with me and you go too.
埃茉娜 你市着孩子最好待在这里
Elena, its 中信 放you stay with the baby.
别担心 我会照顾好一切 我这是怎么了
Dont worry, 1 take care of everything.
者娜 走吧 快点
Lila, let's go, pleasel
帮有我开个门
Open the door.
走吧 记得给我打电话
Go_Call me.
者娜 帮忙开门
Lila, the doorl
之上外套
Get the coats.
我们要把情况都查清楚 快来 炸娜
Now we'l sort it all out. Come on, Lila.
直到门关上的那一刻 我才感受到一阵心痛
Only when the door closed, did 1 feel the wound of that situation.
者娜和尼诡又在一块了 一起市着我妈妈走了
Lila and Nino together again, were taking my mother away.
Hello?
埃莉水 妈妈情况不好 他们正市着她去医院
Elisa, Mamma's not well they're taking her to the hospital.
什么 出什么事了 她在流血 差点融景倒了
What? She was bleeding, she nearly fainted.
哪里在流血
Bleeding from where?
我不知道 下面流出来的
|dunno, from down there.
我不知道霸么样了
| was out of 放.
你在哪儿 我在家 她和和腹娜开千走了
Where are you? |m at home. She's with Lila.
操 和者娜 你残不能叫个救护车吗
Fuck, with Lila? Couldn't you call an ambulance?
当时情况非囊紧急 她很不好 那你也应该跟着一块云呀
Hi was urgent, she wasnt well. You should've gone tool
你 总是    和E>~ 只做你想做的
You only do what suits youl
如果妈妈有死了 你的展心会痛吗
fMamma dies, ill be on your consciencel
马尔切洛
Marcellol
Hello?
和感么了 这位女坏摔倒了吗 没有 她融是突然开始流血
Did the lady fall over? No, she suddenly started bleeding.
小心她的头
Mind her head .
者娜 竺在这 别走 我惑在这儿
Lila, stay with me. 1m here.
他们会对我做什么 没事的
What will they do to me? Nothing.
一切都会好的
Everything's all right.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
你好
Hello?
茉农 他们决定让她住院
Lenw, theyve decided to admit her.
但不用担心 尼诺认识这个医生 他们说一切还在可擎控的范围
Nino knows the doctors, they Say its all under control.
冷静 她现在目己待着吗
stay calm. ls she on her own?
是的
YeS.
他们不让任何人进去
They wont let anyone in.
她不     、\想一个人死去
She doesnt want to die alone.
她不会死
She won't die.
她已经和以前不一样了 她现在很害怕 需要做点什么
She's not like she used to be, she's scared. Do something.
我知道 但这是医院的规定
| know, but those are the hospital rules.
她有问起我吗
Did she ask about me?
她说想让宝宝进去
She said to bring the baby in.
你们现在在干什么呢
What are you two doing now?
尼庄还要和医生待一会儿 我要先离开了
Nino will stay with the doctors for a while, then 川 leave.
好 你别六款着
Good, donttire yourself out.
一有机会尼详融会给你打电话的 好
Nino will call you as soon as he can, okay?
\众主
/~有
Stay calm.
你也要好好休息
不然融没有奶水了 好
Oryour milk will dry up. Yes.
好 谢谢
Thanks.
喂 茉农 我们遇到问题了
Hello? Lenuw, we have a problem.
她情况恶化了吗
ls She Worse?
把那个女士市过来
Bring the lady here right now.
医生很冷静 倒是马尔切洛像个病子
The doctors aren't too worried, its Marcello who's acting crazy.
和马尔切洛有什么关系 谁知道呢
wy Marcello? No ideal
我私下认识这位医生
| know the doctors personally.
这家医院的肿瘤科非营有名
The oncology department in this hospital is excellent.
有钱的地方就有好医生 不取决于你的喜好
Good doctors are where the money is and not with the likes of you.
他正在和尼诺大只
He's arguing with Nino.
我们会把我岳母市到一家好诊所 她会很快鱼鳄的
Welltake my mother-in-law to a nice clinic, she'l recover just fine.
你有什么权利 你他妈算什么东西
What right do you have? Who the hell are you?
马尔切洛 闭嘴吧 滚一边去
Marcello, shut upl Fuck offl
Hello?
告诉尼诺 不用理他
Tell Nino to ignore him.
别管两事 我不想再提醒你
stay out of this, | wont tell you again.
别让我再说第二遍 我可不怕你
1wont say it again.!m not scared of you.
我不想率扯进来
| dont want to get involved in this.
好的
你目己跟这个混香说吧 给我电话
You speak to this asshole. Gimme thatl
茉弄 吃
Lenuw. Hello?
听着 埃莉水不想让你们的母亲竺在医院里
Listen, Elisa doesnt want your mother to stay in the hospital.
会市她去一个好诊所 去卡波迪蒙特 我做得对吗
川take herto a nice clinic in Capodimonte, am |right?
我做得对吗 回答我
Am lright or not? Answer mel
好 首先你冷静一点 我很冷表
Firstly calm down. 1am calm.
你在诊所生孩子 埃莉沙也是
You gave birth in a clinic and so did Elisa，
那为什么你们母亲 非要死在这个狗屎一样的医院里呢
why does your mother have to die in this shithole hospital?
因为那里的医生能照顾好她
The doctors who are treating her work there.
到底谁说了算
Who's in charge here?
你 莉娜 还是我面前那过狗屎
You, Lila or this piece of crap in front of me?
这跟谁襄了算无关 不 有关系
lts not about being in charge. But it is.
要么你告诉你的朋友 我可以审她去卡波迪蒙特
Either you tell your friends 1 can take her to Capodimonte，
么我打断肝人的腿 然后照样市走她
orlll break someone's legs and take her anyway.
你怎么样
How are you?
马尔切洛让莉娜接电话
Put Lila on.
茉农 莉娜 问问尼诡我母亲能不能动
Lenu. Ask Nino if my mother can be moved.
让他去问医生 然后给我回电话
Get him to ask the doctors and call back.
喂 马尔切洛还在跟护士们争执
Yes. Marcello's still raising hell with the nurses.
如果这个畜生没法冷静 我能报警吗
fthis animal doesn't calm down, shall 1 call the police?
好的 你问过她能否移动了吗
Yes. Did you ask if she can be moved?
不 她不能
No, she cantl
你问了还是没问
Did you ask or not?
她不想竺在医院里
She doesnt want to be in the hospital.
从治疗的角度讲 私人诊所是最灶的
In terms of treatments, private clinics are the worstl
好 你先冷衣
Yes, but calm down.
我非芝冷静 好吧 你现在赶紧回来
Im very calm. All right come home right now.
那这儿怎么办
And what about here?
者娜会处理的
Lila can take care of 放.
我不能留刺娜跟那个恤生在一起
| candt leave Lila with that animal.
者娜知道租么照顾目己 我跟你襄了 回家
Lila knows how to look after herse|lfLCome homel
我回来了 嘿
你怎么样 还好
How are you doing? Fine.
伊玛呢
Imma?
她吃过了 现在在睡觉
She's eaten and now she's sleeping.
你狐了吗
Are you hungry?
不 我气疡了 气到已经没胃口了
No, |m so pissed off 1ve lost my appetitel
你根本不知道马尔切洛:索拉拉有多混蛋
You have no jdea how that beast Marcello Solara behavedl
让我们看看到搬谁能赢
Let's see who gets the upper hand.
他好像生了 我也是从老城区走出来的
He's forgetting | come from the neighborhood too.
我感到很愚达 好像还处在年轻时的脆弱与妖妨
| felt stupid, still stuck in my youth, fragile and jealous.
但我实在 没法驱赶走 那些 %令人罕息的幻想
| couldn't chase away those unbearable fantasies.
要朱你一段吗
Do you need a ride?
不用了 恩佐会来
No, Enzo's coming.
阿姨
9Signora.
我是莉娜
It's Lila.
我在这陪着你
|m here with you.
我要走了 现在是早晨了
川 go, its morning now，
护士们进来了
the nurses are coming in.
我没
1m okay.
你确定吗
You Sure?
非常确定
Totally.
你去休息一下吧
Go get Some rest.
等马尔切洛和你妹妹到了 我立马残走
川leave as soon as Marcello and your Sister get here.
你党得他们会回来吗
You think they' be back?
好像他们会放过 大立一场的机会似的
As ifthey'd miss out on making a scene.
回家吧 你已经做得够多了
Go home, youve gone above and beyond.
现在 我把艾玛安顿好 然后我融来
Now 咱get Imma organized and | come.
探视时间是什么时候 我不知道
What are the visiting hours? 1 dont know.
是玫娜吗
ls 让Lila?
晚点儿再联系 让我和她说两名
Speak to you later. Let me speak to her.
她已经挂了 她说了什么 她拒么样
She hung up. How is she?
谁 莉娜
Who? Lila.
关莉娜什么事
What's Lila got to do with it?